A Guide to the Letters of E. E. Cummings 1952-1967
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Letters of E. E. Cummings 1952-1967
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6246-d
This collection contains 18 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was purchased from David Holmes, Bookseller, Philadelphia, Pa., on December 20, 1993.
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of letters and cards from E. E. and Marion Cummings to Arthur Andre Schaffer. Most are pleasant notes of greeting and arrangements to call or visit.
Contents List
- E. E. Cummings to Arthur Andre Schaffer December 5, 1952, APCS
  E. E. Cummings, Cambridge, Massachusetts, to Arthur Andre Schaffer, Fort Slocum, New York, asking him to telephone to set up a time.
- Marion Cummings to Arthur Andre Schaffer December 13, 1952, ALS, 1 p., w/env.
  Marion Cummings, Cambridge, Massachusetts, to Schaffer, Fort Slocum, New York, saying that their trip to New York has been delayed until the 18th and asking if he will still be there.
- Christmas card signed "Cummings & Marion" to Schaffer December 16, 1953, ANS
  Christmas card signed "Cummings & Marion" to Schaffer.
- E. E. Cummings to Schaffer May 23, 1954, APCS
  E. E. Cummings, New York, New York, to Schaffer, F.P.O., New York, New York, re leaving for New Hampshire the following Thursday.
- Marion Cummings to Schaffer November 1, 1954, APCS
  Marion Cummings, New York, New York, to Schaffer, New York, New York, asking him to call her.
- Marion Cummings to Schaffer November 5, 1954, Telegram
  Marion Cummings, New York, New York, to Schaffer, New York, New York, re wrong telephone number.
- E. E. Cummings to Schaffer October 7, 1956, APCS
  E. E. Cummings, Silver Lake, New Hampshire, to Schaffer, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, sending greetings and hoping to see him in New York.
- Christmas card signed "Cummings & Marion" to Schaffer December 21, 1956, ANS
  Christmas card signed "Cummings & Marion" to Schaffer
- Marion Cummings to Schaffer September 9, 1959, APCS
  Marion Cummings, Silver Lake, New Hampshire, to Schaffer, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, writing that they would be delighted to see him in November.
- Marion Cummings to Schaffer January 26, 1960, APCS
  Marion Cummings, New York, New York, to Schaffer, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, looking forward to getting together over the weekend.
- Marion Cummings to Schaffer February 12, 1960, APCS
  Marion Cummings, New York, New York, to Schaffer, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, regretting that he had not shown up at their house as planned.
- Marion Cummings to Schaffer May 3, 1963, APCS
  Marion Cummings, New York, New York, to Schaffer, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, expressing sympathy [for the death of his father] and asking him to visit if ever in New York.
- Marion Cummings to Schaffer August 26, 1963, ALS, 2 p., on 1l., w/ env.
  Marion Cummings, Silver Lake, New Hampshire, to Schaffer, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, sorry that he has been having such a bad time and reminding him of a standing invitation to visit.
- Marion Cummings to Schaffer December 18, 1963, ALS, 2 p., on 1l., w/env.
  Marion Cummings, New York, New York, to Schaffer, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, enclosing a letter in a Christmas card, agreeing "that the letters should be collected," asking if he has seen the last book of poems, 73 Poems, and inquiring about his post-Navy career.
- Marion Cummings to Schaffer December 26, 1965, ANS
  Marion Cummings, New York, New York, to Schaffer, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, written on a Christmas card, concerning the Cummings collection of letters to be done by Fred[erick] Dupee.
- Marion Cummings to Schaffer October 23, 1967, ALS, 2 p., on 1l.
  Marion Cummings to Schaffer, saying that she enjoys having enough money to live well but "the only catch is that having been so spoiled by living all these years with Cummings all else is a let down.
- Christmas card signed "Cummings & Marion" n.d., ANS
  Christmas card signed "Cummings & Marion," regretting that they missed him at the U. N. and thanking him for sending the United Nations publication.
- Envelope addressed to "A. A. Schaffer from "Cummings" September 16, 1952, TD
  Envelope addressed to "A. A. Schaffer, FASRon-THREE, Naval Air Station, Norfolk 11, Virginia" from "Cummings, SilverLake, NH."